<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pedro Vilanova | Genomics Lab</title><link>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-vilanova/</link><atom:link href="https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-vilanova/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Pedro Vilanova</description><generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-vilanova/avatar_hu_925afe14c801e8fc.jpeg</url><title>Pedro Vilanova</title><link>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-vilanova/</link></image><item><title>Chromosome-level comparative genomics and host-specific fungal transcriptomics uncover adaptive virulence strategies in the sugarcane smut pathogen</title><link>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/publication/vilanova_2025/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/publication/vilanova_2025/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pedro Vilanova</title><link>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-vilanova/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-vilanova/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am a biologist with a Master’s in Genetics and Plant Breeding, working with a strong focus on Next Generation Sequencing (NGS) applied to fungal genomics. My research focuses on understanding how fungal genomes function and how gene expression is regulated, with an emphasis on host–pathogen interactions and molecular adaptation. In my work, I apply comparative genomics approaches to explore evolutionary patterns across fungal isolates and perform high-depth RNA-seq analyses to uncover transcriptional changes during infection. In addition to bioinformatics, I also employ molecular biology tools, including cloning and transient expression assays in plant systems, to characterize fungal proteins and investigate their potential roles in pathogenicity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Pedro Marcus de Souza Confort</title><link>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-marcus-de-souza-confort/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/author/pedro-marcus-de-souza-confort/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Plant pathologist and nematologist with expertise in molecular plant–pathogen interactions, host resistance, and bioinformatics. Currently a postdoctoral researcher at the Luiz de Queiroz College of Agriculture (ESALQ/USP), Brazil, investigating transcriptomic responses of sugarcane to Pratylenchus zeae and working on the genome assembly of the same pathogen. My academic journey spans agronomy, plant pathology, and molecular genetics, with experience in both academia and industry, focusing on sustainable crop protection, genetic resistance, and integrative nematology.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Updated chromosome-level genome assembly of Sporisorium scitamineum with improved accuracy and completeness</title><link>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/publication/taniguti_2025/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://genomicslabesalq.github.io/publication/taniguti_2025/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>